Guide to the Alexander L. Fetter Papers SC0567
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alexander L. Fetter papers
1971-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Fetter, Alexander L.
SC0567
18 Linear Feet 20 boxes
Scope and Content
These papers concern his professional activities and his administrative duties at Stanford, 1971-1991. Included are correspondence, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, and articles. In addition to the physics department, several committees are represented, including the Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aids and the Graduate Study Committee.
Biography
Alexander Fetter, theoretical physicist, joined the Stanford faculty in 1965. He received his B.A. at Williams College, 1958, was a Rhodes Scholar at Oxford where he won the Scott Prize in Physics in 1960, and received his Ph.D. at Harvard in 1963. At Stanford, he has also served as associated dean of undergraduate studies, 1977-80, head of the Faculty Senate, 1982-83, and Associate Dean of Humanities and Sciences, 1990-93. He received the Dean's Award for Distinguished Teaching in 1994. He is a fellow of the American Physical Society and the American Association for the Advancement of Science.
Provenance
Gift of Alexander L. Fetter, 1999-2016.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Physics -- Study and teaching.; Walecka, John Dirk; Fetter, Alexander L.; McCormack, Percival D.; Fetter, Alexander L.; Stanford University. Department of Physics; Hallock, Robert Bruce.; Hess, George Burns.; Campbell, Laurence J. (Laurence Joseph); Cole, Milton W.; Chiao, Raymond Y.
- Papers
  - Chron file, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chron file, 1978 Jan. - May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chron file, 1978 June - Dec. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chron file, 1979 Jan. - May (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chron file, 1979 June - Nov (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1972 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1973 - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1974 - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1975 - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1976 – 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1977 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978 - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1978 - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1979 - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1979 - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980 - 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1981 – 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1982 - 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1982 - 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1984 - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1990 - 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1990 - 1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Advanced Placement Committee, 1973-74 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Advisory Board memo, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report, 1976-77 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Applied Physics/Physics Study Group (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Academic Appraisal and Achievement (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aids, 1972-73 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aids, 1972-73 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aids, 1973-74 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Comprehensives, September 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dept. Faculty Papers 1971-1972 [memos etc] (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Papers [articles], 1965-68 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Papers [articles], 1968-69 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Papers [articles], 1969-70 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Papers [articles], 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Five-year plan, October 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hastorf memo, October 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - HEPL (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - History of Science Program, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - History of Science Program, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - History of Science Program, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - History of Science Program, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Klystron royalty funds, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Memo to J. Rosse, March 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Office of the Dean of Undergraduate Studies, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Panel on grading system, 1974-75 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Physics Department, 1972-73 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Physics Department, 1973-74 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Physics Department, 1974-75 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Physics Department, 1975-76 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Physics Department/SLAC (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - SLAC, educational role of, 1969-71 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - SSRL (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - SSRL Review Committee, February 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Science Departments, 1978-79 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Stanford fellowship, 1974-76 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Teaching (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Teaching evaluation, 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Teaching evaluation, 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Theory Search Committee Letter (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Undergraduate Study Curriculum and Teaching Evaluation Committee (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - University papers 1971-72 [memos etc.] (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - University papers 1972-74 [memos etc.] (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Physics Department 1977/78: minutes, general (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Physics Department 1977/78: Graduate Study Committee, advising (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Physics Department 1977/78: 3rd year, 4th year, 5th year, 6th year (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Physics Department 1978/79: minutes, general (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Physics Department 1978/79: advising, grad study (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Physics Department 1978/79: 3rd year, 4th year, 5th year, 6th year and beyond (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Physics Department 1979/80: minutes (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Physics Department 1979/80: general (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Physics Department 1979/80: graduate study, undergraduate study, curriculum and teaching, A-21 and contracts (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Physics Department 1979/80: sponsored projects (governmental) memos (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Physics Department 1980/81: minutes, general (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Physics Department 1980/81: steering committee, undergraduate study, curriculum and evaluation (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Physics Department 1981/82: minutes (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Physics Department 1981/82: undergraduate study (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Physics Department 1981/82: general (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Physics Department 1982/83: minutes, undergraduate study (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Physics Department 1982/83: general (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Physics Department 1983/84: general (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Physics Department 1983/84: minutes, undergraduate study, HandS (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Physics Department 1984/85: general (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Physics Department 1984/85: minutes, undergraduate study (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Physics Department 1984/85: SSRL future (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Physics and Jobs: graduate study committee, newsletters, 1976-77 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Physics and Jobs: minutes, 1976-77 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Physics and Jobs: NSF, placement center, 1976-77 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Physics and Jobs: American Physical Society, 1976-77 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2014-131
  - Hiring, Tenure & Promotion files (Box 5)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-167
  - National University of Singapore: Institute for Mathematical Sciences (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ELAF XXXVIII (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ELAF XXXVIII Mexico, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Paris/Aftalion, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - APS Climate Change, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - San Feliu, 2009 Sep 5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Int. Laser Phys Barcelona, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ICTP, 2009 May 04 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AAAS Sec B, 2009 Jan (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - March Meeting, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - CASTU Conference, 2008 Oct (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - LT 25, 2008 Aug (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Les Treilles, 2008 Jul (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - APS March Meeting New Orleans, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dartmouth Ext. Review, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - NUS Singapore, 2007 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - LPHYS Mexico, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - APS March Meeting Austin, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - IPAM Workshop UCLA, 2003 Feb (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Oulu, Finland Workshop, 2003 Jan 4 8 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - LT 23, 2002 Aug (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Trento BEC, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Foundation de Treilles Conf, 2002 Jun (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ICAP, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - APS March Meeting, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Aspen Winter Conf, 2012 Feb (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Aspen Center for Physics, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Prof. Fetter's notes, 2001 Jul 01 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Aspen, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - CMT 25, 2001 Dec (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lansane, 2001 Jun (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Paris, Lansane, Charoney, 2001 Jun (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cargese, 2014 Jul (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Trento Winter, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Talks, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Prof. A. Fetter, 2013 Oct (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Prof. A. Fetter, 2004 Feb (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Copenhagen Asocc. Prof., 2004 Jan (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - APS March meeting abstract, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Crete, 2003 Sep (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Prof. A. Fetter papers (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Talks, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Notes, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Aspen Center for Physics (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Aspen, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Phys 220, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Phys 221, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Los Alamos, 2007 Jul (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Paris, 2007 Apr (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ULM, 2007 May 25 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Superfluids under rotation, 2007 Apr (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Prof. A. Fetter papers Jerusalem, 2007 Apr (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Kauli Santa Barbara, 2007 Apr (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Denver March meeting, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - SIAM, Seattle, 2006 Sep 10 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - LPHYS Lousanne, 2006 Jul (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Nizhny Novgorod, 2006 Jun (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Baltimore, 2006 Mar (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Aspen, 2016 Jan (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Rice Playfield Visiting Committee, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Warwick Trento, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - INT workshop, 2005 Aug (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - ICTP workshop, 2005 Jul (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - OSU workshop, 2005 Apr (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - UBCTall, 2005 Apr 04 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - March Meeting, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Banff, 2005 Feb (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Boulder, 2004 Jul (Box 4, Folder 21)